Finding Aid for the Phil Doran Papers PASC.0351
UCLA Library Special Collections
Phil Doran papers
1967-1971
UCLA Library Special Collections
Doran, Phil
PASC.0351
1.4 Linear Feet (3 boxes and 1 half document box)
Phil Doran was a television writer who wrote for game shows and late night talk shows in the late 1960's and early 1970's. The collection consists of his project ideas, game show questions, talk show host monologues and a small number of business notes.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9966850463606533
Biography
Phil Doran graduated from Indiana University in 1965 with a B.S. in Radio-TV Production/Direction. From 1965-1967 Doran worked for various advertising agencies writing advertisements for radio, print and television. In August of 1967, Doran was hired by Chuck Barris Productions to write questions and coordinate contestants for the game shows The Newlywed Game, The Dating Game and The Family Game. He was hired as the head writer for The Joey Bishop Show in November of 1968, a position he retained until the show's cancellation in November 1969. In 1971, Doran worked as the talent coordinator for The Merv Griffin Show for which he wrote guest introduction and interview sets. Doran later went on to write for the daytime game show The Amateur's Guide to Love in 1972. Doran went on to write and produce such shows as Who's The Boss?, The Wonder Years and Sanford and Son. In 2006, he published the novel The Reluctant Tuscan.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials related to the early career of television writer Phil Doran. Included are project ideas, game show material, television talk show host monologues and a small number of business notes. The bulk of the materials consist of host monologues and guest questions for The Joey Bishop Show and The Merv Griffin Show. There are also segment bits for the short lived daytime game show The Amateur's Guide to Love, a game involving videotaped sequences from around the greater Los Angeles area. Also included are questions and notes for the game shows The Newlywed Game and The Family Game.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder titles assigned by the processor, which reflect the contents of the files.
Television writers -- Archives.; Doran, Phil
- Amateur's Guide to Love - show segment bit drafts A-J, no date (Box 4)
- Amateur's Guide to Love - show segment bit drafts K-W, no date (Box 4)
- Amateur's Guide to Love - show segment bits A-J, no date (Box 4)
- Amateur's Guide to Love - show segment bits K-W, no date (Box 4)
- Dating Game (The) notes for announcer and contestants, no date (Box 1)
  General note
  Appears to be notes for The Dating Game.
- Family Game (The) - question drafts and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Family Game (The) - question drafts and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Family Game (The) - questions for contestants, 1967 (Box 1)
- Family Game (The) - questions for contestants, 1967 (Box 1)
- Ideas, no date (Box 1)
- Joey Bishop Show - ideas, no date (Box 3)
  Appears to be material for the Joey Bishop late night talk show that ran 1967-1969
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Oct (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Aug (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, June (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, May (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Apr (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Mar (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Nov (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Jan (Box 1)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Sept (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Feb. (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, no date (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, July (Box 2)
- Joey Bishop Show - monologue jokes, Dec (Box 2)
- Laugh In idea, no date (Box 1)
- Letter from Doran to Bob Shanks re: employment with Merv Griffin Productions, 1969 Dec 2 (Box 1)
- London Lee project idea, no date (Box 1)
- Mating the Write Way! - handwriting guide, no date (Box 1)
  Ephemera possibly related to The Dating Game.
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Oct (Box 4)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, no date (Box 4)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1972 Jan (Box 4)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Nov (Box 4)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Sept (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Mar (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Jan (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Feb (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Aug (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 Apr (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 May (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 June (Box 3)
- Merv Griffin Show (The) - sets of introductions and questions, 1971 July (Box 3)
- Mr. President project idea, no date (Box 1)
- Newlywed Game (The) - question drafts and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Newlywed Game (The) - question drafts and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Newlywed Game (The) - question drafts and notes, no date (Box 1)
- Phil Doran Resume, 1969 (Box 1)
- Rejection letter to Doran from Ed Weinberger re: Cosby Show, 1969 Aug 21 (Box 1)
- Unidentified ideas, no date (Box 3)
  Possibly related to Merv Griffin Show; found among other possible Merv Griffin materials.
- Unidentified Project Idea, no date (Box 1)